Guide to the Victor Remer Historical Archives of the Children's Aid Society 1836-2006 (bulk 1853-1947) MS 111
New-York Historical Society
- Series IX - Facilities Records: Industrial Schools, Lodging Houses, Summer Camps, and Farm Schools, 1854-1972 and undated; 1854-1958
  - Subseries IX.2 - Facilities, Alphabetical, 1854-1974 and undated
    - Bowdoin Farm: Alumni Society reunion materials (invitations, memos), 1950 (Offsite-box 40, Folder 39)
    - Bowdoin Farm: Miscellaneous reports and correspondence from final years (includes photos), 1951 May-1958 July (Offsite-box 40, Folder 40)
    - Bowdoin Farm: CAS statistical reports, 1955-1958 (Offsite-box 40, Folder 41)
    - Bowdoin Farm: monthly reports to Deptartment of Social welfare and notice of final report and suspension of program, 1956 January-1958 August (Offsite-box 41, Folder 1)
    - Bowdoin Farm: reports to the NYC Board of Education, 1956 February-1957 March (Offsite-box 41, Folder 2)
    - Bowdoin Farm and Camp layout, undated (Offsite-box 41, Folder 3)
    - Bowdoin Farm: forms and materials given to boy and family upon admittance to Bowdoin Farm, undated (Offsite-box 41, Folder 4)
    - Bowdoin Farm: miscellaneous (memo, dedication, presentation), 1940, 1942 and undated (Offsite-box 41, Folder 5)
    - Bowdoin Farm: miscellaneous blank Department of Social Welfare forms from Bowdoin Farm files, undated (Offsite-box 41, Folder 6)
    - Brace Farm: monthly reports, 1900 August, 1901 November, 1902 January-July and December (Offsite-box 41, Folder 7)
    - Brace Farm: annual report of the superintendent, circa 1900 (Offsite-box 41, Folder 8)
    - Brace Farm: Dairy Cash Book (includes loose correspondence), 1904-1907 (Offsite-box 1047, Volume 280)
    - Brace Farm: property surveys 1925 (1) and 1928 (3), 1925, 1928 (Offsite-box OS 2, Folder 3)
    - Brace Farm: inspection reports, 1935 March and April (Offsite-box 41, Folder 9)
    - Brace Farm: correspondence, memos [from the files of Arthur Huck], 1935 September 27-1939 September 30 and undated (Offsite-box 41, Folder 10)
    - Brace Farm: Statistics for the Year 1936, circa 1936 December 31 (Offsite-box 41, Folder 11)
    - Brace Farm: memos, internal reports, correspondence [from the files of Nora Johnson], 1940 April 9-1948 August 30 and undated (Offsite-box 41, Folder 12)
    - Brace Farm: Boarding Intake, 1941 November-1944 September (Offsite-box 1047, Volume 281)
    - Brace Farm: list of boys treated, problems, dispositions, 1942-1945 (Offsite-box OS 2, Folder 4)
    - The Children's Home Daily Record Book (Narratives re: infants and small children brought in by mothers unable to care for them, for temporary homes or adoption), 1867 January 1-1868 July 2 (Offsite-box 1047, Volume 282)
    - [Chrystie Street Lodging House] statistical reports (disbound from volume), 1942-1946 and 1948 (Offsite-box 41, Folder 13)
    - Columbus Hill Day Nursery, Receipts and Expenses, 1929-1932 (Offsite-box 1048, Volume 283)
    - Duane Street School, Visitor's Book, 1875-1907 (Offsite-box 1048, Volume 284)
    - East River School, Visitor's Book, 1889-1913 (Offsite-box 1048, Volume 285)
    - East Side Industrial School: financial materials (receipts, 1 ledger page, 2 letters from Principal Alice Hill), 1894, 1897 (Offsite-box 41, Folder 14)
    - East Side Lodging House Monthly Accounts, 1894-1897 (Offsite-box 1121, Volume 286)
    - Eleventh Ward Lodging House: statistical and financial reports, 1866, June-August (Offsite-box 41, Folder 15)
    - Eleventh Ward School and Lodging House, Visitor's Register [also labeled and including Tompkins Square Lodging House], 1872-1925 (Offsite-box 1048, Volume 287)
    - Eleventh Ward School and Lodging House: Monthly Statistical Reports (includes nationality, parentage, reading ability, occupations, expenses, etc.), 1873-1881 (Offsite-box 1122, Volume 288)
    - Eleventh Ward Lodging House: "Reasons Assigned by 100 Boys for their having to seek a home at the Eleventh Ward Lodging House", circa 1874 (Offsite-box 41, Folder 16)
    - Eleventh Ward School and Lodging House: Donations Received, 1875-1910 (Offsite-box 1048, Volume 289)
    - Elizabeth Home for Girls: Register, 1899-1904 (Offsite-box 1048, Volume 290)
    - Elizabeth Home and Training School for Girls: monthly reports, 1901 October-1902 September (Offsite-box 41, Folder 17)
    - Elizabeth Home: correspondence from Superintendent E.S. Hurley to "Mr. Grimm" re: various cases (3 letters), 1902 January 29-June 10 (Offsite-box 41, Folder 18)
    - Elizabeth Home for Girls: Daily Register, 1908 October-1911 September (Offsite-box 1122, Volume 291)
    - Elizabeth Home for Girls: Register and Reports(includes folder of loose materials including photograph), 1909-1930 (Offsite-box 1049, Volume 292)
    - Elizabeth Home: Register (disbound binder), 1923 October-December (Offsite-box 41, Folder 19)
    - Elizabeth Home: Register (disbound binder), 1924 January-September and undated (Offsite-box 41, Folder 20)
    - Elizabeth Home: Register (disbound binder), 1926 March-September and undated (Offsite-box 41, Folder 21)
    - Elizabeth (Wheeler) Home: Requisitions for Supplies(includes folder of loose pages), 1928-1930 (Offsite-box 1049, Volume 293)
    - Emergency Shelter for Women and Children, aka Elizabeth Home Annex: monthly reports, 1901 December-1902 September (Offsite-box 41, Folder 22)
    - Emergency Shelter for Women and Children, aka Elizabeth Home Annex: Register, 1901 December-1909 March (Offsite-box 1049, Volume 294)
    - Emergency Shelter for Women and Children: Expenses 1902-1914 (Offsite-box 1049, Volume 295)
    - Emergency Shelter for Women and Children: Narrative Record Book No. 1, 1904-1907 (Offsite-box 1049, Volume 296)
    - Emergency Shelter for Women and Children: Narrative Record Book No. 2, 1908-1913 (Offsite-box 1050, Volume 297)
    - Emergency Shelter for Women and Children: Narrative Reports arranged alphabetically by individual(some pages cut out), 1908-1909 (Offsite-box 1050, Volume 298)
    - Emergency Shelter for Women and Children: Narrative Reports arranged alphabetically by individual, 1910 (Offsite-box 1050, Volume 299)
    - Emergency Shelter for Women and Children: Monthly Statistical Record, 1911-1913 (Offsite-box 1050, Volume 300)
    - Emergency Shelter for Women and Children: Narrative Record Book No. 3, 1913-1926 (Offsite-box 1050, Volume 301)
    - Emergency Shelter for Women and Children: Monthly Statistical Record, 1917-1930 (Offsite-box 1050, Volume 302)
    - Emergency Shelter for Women and Children:Register (non-narrative)(includes loose applications), 1922-1926 (Offsite-box 1050, Volume 303)
    - Emergency Shelter for Women and Children: Narrative Record Book No. 4, 1926-1930 (Offsite-box 1051, Volume 304)
    - Emergency Shelter for Women and Children: Register (non-narrative), 1929-1930 (Offsite-box 1051, Volume 305)
    - Fifth Ward Industrial School [141 Hudson Street]: Visitor's Book, 1874-1899 (Offsite-box 1051, Volume 306)
    - Fifty-Third Street Industrial School: program for benefit, 1886 April 19 (Offsite-box 41, Folder 23)
    - Fifty-Third Street Industrial School: notes on cases, undated (Offsite-box 41, Folder 24)
    - Forty-Fourth Street Lodging House: monthly reports and one piece of accompanying correspondence, 1901 October-1902 September (Offsite-box 41, Folder 25)
    - Forty-Fourth Street Lodging House and Harlem Boys' Hotel: photocopies of fliers for World War I patriotic rallies, 1917 May (Offsite-box 41, Folder 26)
    - German Industrial School, Donations, 1866-1867 (Offsite-box 1051, Volume 307)
    - German Industrial School, Subscriptions, 1867-1872 (Offsite-box 1051, Volume 308)
    - Girls Lodging House: Narrative Dispositions Log, 1862 June-1869 January (Offsite-box 1051, Volume 309)
    - Girls Lodging House: disbound pages from a log book listing info about residents 1866-1868 and donations 1862-1868 (Offsite-box 41, Folder 27)
    - Girls Lodging House: Register (names, dates, statistical), 1864-1865 (Offsite-box 1122, Volume 310)
    - [Girls Lodging House]: list of girls who obtained situations or employment, 1866 August (Offsite-box 41, Folder 28)
    - Girls Lodging House: Receipts and Expenses, 1866-1867 (Offsite-box 1051, Volume 311)
    - Girls Lodging House: Narrative Register, circa 1860s (Offsite-box 1052, Volume 312)
    - [Girls Lodging House]: Attendance Record at Sewing Machine Class, 1870-1874 (Offsite-box 1052, Volume 313)
    - Girls Lodging House: Register, 1872-1880 (Offsite-box 1052, Volume 314)
    - Girls Lodging House: Narrative Record Book, 1872-1911 (Offsite-box 1052, Volume 315)
    - Girls Lodging House: Night Register, 1873-1874 (Offsite-box 1052, Volume 316)
    - Girls Lodging House: Register, 1880-1889 (Offsite-box 1052, Offsite-box 317)
    - Girls Lodging House: Receipts and Expenses, 1886-1896 (Offsite-box 1053, Volume 318)
    - Girls Lodging House: Register, 1890-1899 (Offsite-box 1053, Volume 319)
    - Girls Lodging House: Night Register, 1891-1894 (Offsite-box 1053, Volume 320)
    - Girls Lodging House: Ladies Committee and Names of Ladies Interested in the Girls Lodging House, undated (Offsite-box 1053, Volume 321)
    - Goodhue Home: miniature address book belonging to a child who lived at Goodhue, 1929-1930 (Offsite-box 41, Folder 29)
    - Goodhue Home: reports, correspondence [from the files of Arthur Huck], 1932 January 31-1940 November 4 and 1965 (Offsite-box 41, Folder 30)
    - Goodhue Recreation Center report by Director William Kirchner, 1936 May 1-September 15 (Offsite-box 41, Folder 31)
    - Goodhue Home - map (photocopy), undated (Offsite-box OS 2, Folder 6)
    - Henrietta Industrial School (54th Street Industrial School): Visitor's Book, 1892-1939 (Volume 322)
    - Henrietta School: School Savings Bank passbooks (5), 1927-1931 (Offsite-box 41, Folder 32)
    - Italian School: donations to the Italian School fund, circa 1874 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 1)
    - Italian School: "reports presented at the meeting celebrating the opening of the new building", 1875 April 29 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 2)
    - [Italian School]: Register of Pupils, 1908-1914 (Offsite-box 1122, Volume 323)
    - Italian School: "La Scuola Italiana dei Cinque Punti" Report printed for distribution at the Turin Exhibition, 1911 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 3)
    - Italian School: Italian School Bulletin, vol. 3, no. 1, 1915 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 4)
    - Italian School: Open Air Class and Nursery (and Avenue B Nursery) Expenses (includes loose correspondence), 1922-1927 (Offsite-box 1053, Volume 324)
    - Italian School: pamphlet (photocopy only), circa 1920's (Offsite-box 42, Folder 5)
    - Italian School: "A brief history of the Italian School, later known as the James Children Center, as given by Lillian J. Weygandt at meeting of James Boys Club", 1933 October 13 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 6)
    - Italian School: speeches upon the unveiling of the Weygandt Memorial Plaque - history of the Italian School and tributes to Louisa de Ferrari Weygandt, principal 1860-1921 and Lillian Weygandt, principal 1921-1930, 1939 July 25 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 7)
    - Jones Memorial Children's Center: Invitation to opening of new annex, and pamphlet re: facilities, 1936 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 8)
    - Jones Memorial Children's Center: typescripts of press releases, correspondence, internal documents, re: opening of new annex, 1936 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 9)
    - Jones Memorial Children's Center: reports and memos, 1954-1958 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 10)
    - Kips Bay Boys' Club: 2 typed histories upon changes to the facilities, circa 1928 and undated (Offsite-box 42, Folder 11)
    - Kips Bay Boys' Club: map showing Kips' Bay Boys' Club properties with assessments in NYC context, 1947 (Offsite-box OS 2, Folder 6)
    - Mott Street School: Emma E. Smith's "Visitor's Book," narrative reports arranged alphabetically by individual, 1913-1914 (Offsite-box 1054, Volume 325)
    - Newsboys Lodging House and Girls Lodging House: Subscriptions, undated, circa 1861-1892 (Offsite-box 1054, Volume 326)
    - Newsboys Lodging House: Subscriptions, undated, circa 1861-1892 (Offsite-box 1054, Volume 327)
    - Newsboys Lodging House: Subscriptions, undated, circa 1861-1892 (Offsite-box 1054, Volume 328)
    - Newsboys Lodging House [on 11th St.; may be Eleventh Ward Lodging House]: list of boys and breakdown of meals, lodging, 1873 (Offsite-box 1054, Volume 329)
    - Newsboys' Lodging House: "Causes of application in 100 boys", circa 1874 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 12)
    - Newsboys Lodging House: Visitor's Register 1887-1915 (Offsite-box 1054, Volume 330)
    - Newsboys' Lodging House - testimonial letters from residents (4 originals), 1889 and undated (Offsite-box 42, Folder 13)
    - Newsboys' Lodging House - monthly reports (missing September 1902), 1901 October-1902 October (Offsite-box 42, Folder 14)
    - Newsboys' Lodging House - report on Brace Memorial fund and trade classes for boys, circa 1906 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 15)
    - Newsboys' Lodging House and Brace Farm School - Promotional Card Separated from Case File 5541, circa 1908 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 16)
    - Newsboys' Lodging House - Inspection Report, 1911 July 26 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 17)
    - Brace Memorial Newsboys' House: programs for annual Washington's Birthday celebration and dinner (photocopies only), 1913-1917 and 1919 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 18)
    - Brace Memorial Newsboys' House: Invitations and programs for annual Christmas festivities (photocopies only), 1915-1918 and circa 1928 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 19)
    - Brace Memorial Newsboys' House: programs for second (original) and fifth (photocopy) annual entertainment and vaudeville by "our friends from the boys' club", 1915, 1918 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 20)
    - Brace Memorial Newsboys' Home Newsletter: "Brace Memorial News" issued by Brace Memorial Senior Club, Vol. I No. 1 and Vol. I No. 2, 1915 December and 1916 January (Offsite-box 42, Folder 21)
    - Brace Memorial Newsboys' Home Newsletter, Vol. I No. 3 (photocopy only), Vol. I No. 4 (original), and Vol. I No. 5 (photocopy only), 1916 February 1, February 22, March 17 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 22)
    - Brace Memorial Newsboys' Home: Program for first annual minstrel show of the Brace Memorial Senior Club, 1916 March 17 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 23)
    - Brace Memorial Newsboys' House: Invitation/program for intersettlement debate (1916) and annual reunion and dance of alumni boys (1920) and misc. other events (photocopies only), 1916, 1920, and undated (Offsite-box 42, Folder 24)
    - Brace Memorial Newsboys' House: programs for annual spring celebation and athletic meet (3 photocopies, 1 1926 original), 1916, 1919. 1925, 1926 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 25)
    - Brace Memorial Newsboys' Home Newsletter, Vol. 2, No. 4, 1916 November 29 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 26)
    - Brace Memorial Newsboys' House: Invitation and program for second annual minstrel show of the Senior Club, 1917 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 27)
    - Brace Memorial Newsboys' House: Lyrics for songs in the Senior Club minstrel show (2 copies), circa 1917 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 28)
    - Brace Memorial Newsboys' House: programs for annual dinners of the Senior Club (photocopies only), 1917, 1918, 1919, 1921 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 29)
    - Brace Memorial Newsboys' Home Newsletter, Vol. 3, No. 1, and Vol. 3, No. 3 (missing No. 2), 1917 December 25 and 1918 February (Offsite-box 42, Folder 30)
    - Brace Memorial Newsboys' House: Correspondence from the office of Brooklyn Borough President and Charles Guggenheimer to William Butcher, Superintendent, re: speakers at Washington's Birthday Dinner, 1918 February (Offsite-box 42, Folder 31)
    - Brace Memorial Newsboys' Home Newsletter, Vol. 4, No. 2 (2 copies) and vol. 4, No. 3, 1919 February 22 and 1920 February 23 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 32)
    - Card produced and signed by a newsboy, soliciting money, and photocopied letter from same "king of the newsboys", 1919 June 6 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 33)
    - Brace Memorial Newsboys' House: programs for annual Christmas festivities (4 original programs), 1922, 1923, 1924, 1930 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 34)
    - Brace Memorial Newsboys' House: programs for annual Washington's Birthday celebration and dinner (3 original programs), 1922, 1924, 1925 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 35)
    - Brace Memorial Newsboys' House: program for the first annual minstrel show of the Lane and Osborn Boys' Clubs, 1924 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 36)
    - Brace Memorial Newsboys' House: Invitation/program for a series of profitable Sunday Evenings [1925-1926] anad dedication of a plaque [1931] (originals), circa 1925-1926 and circa 1931 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 37)
    - Brace Memorial Newsboys' House: Invitation and program for housewarming of modernized building, 1926 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 38)
    - Brace Memorial Newsboys Lodging House: Visitor's Register, 1926-1947 (Offsite-box 1054, Volume 331)
    - Brace Memorial Newsboys' House: Christmas cards sent by Director William Lewis Butcher (2 cards), circa 1920s (Offsite-box 42, Folder 39)
    - Brace Memorial Newsboys' House: blank letterhead stationery (2 sheets, different designs), circa 1920s (Offsite-box 42, Folder 40)
    - Brace Memorial Newsboys' House: "The Story of Brace Memorial Newsboys' House" draft and fact sheet, CAS author unknown, 1931 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 41)
    - Brace Memorial Newsboys' House: Statistical breakdown of boys' legal residences, and their population numbers, 1932 November 1-1933 February 1 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 42)
    - Brace Memorial Newsboys' House and Bowdoin Farm Training Program: "Information Culled from Older Boy Questionnaire", circa 1933 February (Offsite-box 42, Folder 43)
    - [Brace Memorial Newsboys' House]: Information culled from questionnaire, circa 1933 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 44)
    - Brace Memorial Newsboys' House: Statistical reports, annual, by month (including age, parentage, nativity, education, and religion), 1934-1941 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 45)
    - [Brace Memorial Newsboys' House]: "States from which boys came", 1937 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 46)
    - Brace Memorial Newsboys' House: Correspondence from a former newsboy to Director G.E.W. Blum, and reply, 1938 November 25 and 28 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 47)
    - Brace Memorial Newsboys' House: Breakdown of agencies referring boys, 1939 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 48)
    - Brace Memorial Newsboys' House: notice of suspension of facilities, and conversion to Coast Guard use, 1942 December 21 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 49)
    - Brace Memorial Newsboys' House: "The Crossroads": an artist's representation of lodging house accomplishments, undated (Offsite-box OS 2, Folder 5)
    - Rhinelander School: Annual Report, 1901 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 50)
    - Rivington Street Lodging House: Subscriptions and Appeal, circa 1870 (Offsite-box 1054, Volume 332)
    - Rivington Street Lodging House: "Causes of Homelessness", 1874 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 51)
    - Sixth Street Industrial School: Testimonial from former student (photocopy), 1978 March 23 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 52)
    - Sullivan Street School: Visitor's Register, 1880-1915 (Offsite-box 1054, Volume 333)
    - Sullivan Street School: Financial Record, 1913-1914 (Offsite-box 1054, Volume 334)
    - Sullivan Street School: pamphlet, circa 1920s (Offsite-box 42, Folder 53)
    - Tompkins Square Lodging House: Dispositions of Boys (name, age, nationality, parentage, destination), 1891-1906 (Offsite-box 1054, Volume 335)
    - Tompkins Square Boys' Lodging House and Industrial School: Narrative Record, 1898-1904 (Offsite-box 1054, Volume 336)
    - Tompkins Square Lodging House: monthly reports, 1901 October-1902 September (Offsite-box 42, Folder 54)
    - Tompkins Square Boys' Home: Visitor's Register, 1903-1911 (Offsite-box 1055, Volume 337)
    - Tompkins Square Lodging House: Boys' Bank Accounts 1904-1905 and Expenses January 1904 (Offsite-box 1055, Volume 338)
    - Tompkins Square Lodging House: Boys' Bank Accounts, 1905-1906 (Offsite-box 1055, Volume 339)
    - Twenty-Fourth Street Boys and Girls Lodging House (AKA "Refuge"): Receipts, 1866 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 55)
    - Utopia Children's House: "Four Years of work at Utopia Children's House 170 W. 130th Street 1928-1932" (report - photocopy only) (Offsite-box 42, Folder 56)
    - Wendell Boys' Club: Correspondence and Inspection Reports, 1917 November 22-1918 May 30 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 57)
    - Wendell Boys' Club [in former West Side Boys' Home]: Minutes, 1917 (Offsite-box 1055, Volume 340)
    - Wendell Committee Ledger, 1918-1921 (Offsite-box 1055, Volume 341)
    - "Wendell Unit 28" [Wendell Boys' Club?], 1919 January 15-1919 March 21 (Offsite-box 1055, Volume 342)
    - "Wendell Unit 28" [Wendell Boys' Club?], 1919 June 12-1920 July 3 (Offsite-box 1055, Volume 343)
    - West Side Lodging House: monthly reports, 1901 October-1902 September (Offsite-box 42, Folder 58)
    - West Side Lodging House: Expenses and Statistics, 1901-1918 (Offsite-box 1056, Volume 344)
    - West Side Boys' Home, Visitor's Register, 1903-1919 (Offsite-box 1056, Volume 345)
    - West Side Boys' Home: program for 3rd Annual Minstrels (photocopy only), 1913 January 1 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 59)
    - West Side Boys' Home, Coat Room Receipts 1914-1916 (loose correspondence 1913-1917 interleaved) (Offsite-box 1056, Volume 346)
    - West Side Health School/Children's Center: Annual report (1926) and Information about facility (1939), 1926-1939 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 60)
    - Unidentified Industrial School: top half of "Testimonial" document/certificate (2 copies), undated (Offsite-box 42, Folder 61)
    - Unidentified Industrial School (?): Student Drawings of Furniture, etc. (2 folders), 1906 January (Offsite-box 1018, Folder 3-4)
    - Unidentified Boys Lodging House: Intake Forms, 1901-1903 (Offsite-box 1056, Volume 347)
    - Unidentified Boys Lodging House: Register(oversize), 1902-1904 (Offsite-box 1123, Volume 348)
    - Unidentified Boys Lodging House: Intake Forms, 1904-1908 (Offsite-box 1123, Volume 349)
    - Unidentified Facility for Men: Register, 1913-1920 (Offsite-box 1056, Volume 350)
- Series X - Convalescent Facilities and Medical Programs, 1885-1965
  The materials in this series are arranged in 2 subseries:
  X.1 The Sick Children's Mission/Medical Bureau/Medical Department - Chronological
  X.2 Convalescent Facilities -Alphabetical.
  Both subseries include volumes interfiled with boxes. The boxed materials in both subseries include correspondence, reports, referral cards, and pamphlets. Two folders have been separated to an oversized (OS) box, noted in the container list.
  History of CAS Medical Programs
  The Children's Aid Society began its Sick Children's Mission in 1873. In this program, CAS physicians, nurses, and "visitors" called on poor, sick children in their tenement homes, dispensed medicine and food, instructed mothers on nutrition and other matters, and referred children to CAS convalescent facilities outside the city. The series includes reports by these visitors, and some referral and physician's recommendation cards. It also includes reports, pamphlets, volumes, and correspondence related to the convalescent facilities of the CAS to which children were referred.